# **CURRICULUM VITA**

### **Personal Information**

Name: Rand Shakir Mahmood.

Phone Number: +964 0771-8469743.

E-mail: engrand.shakir@gmail.com.

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rand-shakir-52025915a

Nationality: Iraqi.

Address: Baghdad-Iraq.

## **Profile statement**

An ambitious and experienced civil engineer who possesses the required level of strong initiative, motivation and drive needed to achieve long-term success. Having a proactive approach to career development, a clear and logical mind with a practical approach to problem-solving, with more than 2 years of experience in managing and leading teams across multiple sectors. I am eager to learn, I enjoy overcoming challenges, and I have a genuine interest in Business Management and making organizations successful.

### **Education**

Civil Engineering B.SC, Baghdad University/College of Engineering -Graduates 2011.

#### **Certifications**

- IBE
- Auto Cad.

# **Experience**

- Assistant engineer
- At mayoralty of Baghdad municipality office. June 2012- May 2013

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Assisting in the supervision of civil, building works or services contracts.
- Challenging structural architects in terms of proposed solutions i.e. construction cost, technical requirements, sustainability, suitability or quality.



#### • Accountant

at private collage

**September 2013- May 2015** 

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Working within a financial accounting team and responsible for preparing, examining, analyzing accounting records, financial statements, and other financial reports.
- Duties; Reporting to senior managers regarding the company's finances.

### • Data Entry.

• at private collage

September 2013-May 2015

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Clerk enters information into computer databases for effective record keeping.
- Daily responsibilities include: Organizing files and collecting data to be entered into the computer.
- Compiling, verifying accuracy and sorting information to prepare source data for computer entry.

## • Resident engineer

at private collage

September 2013-May 2015

#### **Responsibilities:**

- Supervise the planning, coordination and implementation of construction projects
- Lead projects and supervise staff
- Report to a contractor or general manager.

# Languages:

	Understanding	Reading	Writing	Speaking
Arabic (the native language)	Excellent	Excellent	Excellent	Excellent
English	Very good	Very good	Very good	Very good
French	Intermediate	Intermediate	Intermediate	Intermediate

# **Knowledge and Skills:**

- Planning
- Project estimation
- Project management

- Surveying
- Strategic planning
- Team leadership
- Customer service
- Negotiation
- Microsoft Office (Word-Power Point-Access-Excel-outlook,...).
- Microsoft Project. (Time Schedule).

# **Reference:**

• Available if required.